

Muhammad Salman

Nationality: Pakistani Date of birth: 13/02/1998 Gender: Male

№ Whatsapp Messenger: 07903556002

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/itxmsalman/

Website: www.skgraphic.shop

• Home: 442A LODGE AVENUE DAGENHAM ESSEX, RM9 4QS London (United

Kingdom)

ABOUT ME

I am a student of MSc computer science at The University of Law. I've done a bachelor's and master's in political science from the University of Peshawar. I've done DIT from the Technical board. I've worked in different institutes as an IT Assistant & computer operator for more than 5 years. Besides, also I've provided services of Graphics Design as a freelancer on different online platforms.

CERTIFICATES

Foundations of Cybersecurity

[29/05/2023]

an online non-credit course authorized by Google and offered through Coursera

Verification

https://coursera.org/verify/H7NFVBHEFS8S

IT Technical Support Fundamentals

[06/12/2022]

an online non-credit course authorized by Google and offered through Coursera

Verification

https://coursera.org/verify/ZQS7DGTHCKY4

The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking

[29/03/2023]

an online non-credit course authorized by Google and offered through Coursera

Verification

https://coursera.org/verify/6Y3D7GJZLPC4

WORK EXPERIENCE

Computer operator

KTH Khyber Teaching Hospital (IBP) [01/08/2017 – 14/01/2020]

City: Peshawar, Pakistan

Country: Pakistan

Website: https://kth.edu.pk/ Email address: lnfo@kth.edu.pk Name of unit or department: Health Sector - Business or sector: Other service activities

Major responsibilities:

- Using HMIS software
- OPD & EMERGENCY patient registration
- Admissions & cancellation of patients invoices
- CPT invoicing & receiving payments from patients
- Reporting and verification
- Employee ID Registration & service card
- Backup support to the IT office
- IBP patient's radiology entry in HMIS
- Reporting to IBP Manager
- Network issue resolving if there is no one present in IT
- Official operations
- Support Team
- Routine examinations of information

Assistant of IT Manager

Rafagat Babar & Co Chartered Accounts [20/01/2020 - 21/01/2022]

City: Peshawar, Pakistan **Country:** Pakistan

Website: https://www.rafaqatbabar.com/
Email address: zeeshan@rafaqatbabar.com/

Name of unit or department: Rafaqat Babar & Co. Chartered Accountants - Business or sector: Administrative

and support service activities

Major responsibilities:

- Continuously monitoring and reacting to IT operations schedules
- Software installations to perform high-duty
- Backups from users and uploads to servers with due time
- Scanning & compressing and storing data
- Reporting all daily work to the IT Manager
- Working on ERP system, To Adjustment of Delivery Challan.
- Maintaining and supplying inventory by regularly checking stock levels to determine the overall inventory level.
- Wi-Fi control and adding users to micro tech
- Ensure that printers, cartridges, and other equipment are fully stocked and ready for use
- Perform light maintenance on equipment and systems in order to prevent problems or errors
- Ensure software updates are installed and bugs are fixed as needed
- Troubleshoot software and hardware problems that are reported and resolve them
- Report any problems or malfunctions to the necessary computer technician
- Check that local area networks are functioning properly, and resolve or repair issues when they are identified

Network Admin

Frontier Green Wood Industries (PVT) Ltd. [01/02/2022 – 30/11/2022]

City: Peshawar, Pakistan **Country:** Pakistan

Major responsibilities:

- Coordinate office activities and operations to secure efficiency and compliance with company policies.
- Continuously monitoring and reacting to IT operations schedules
- Print all the official emails and sign from the concerned department's HODs
- Responsible for totals intercom and also responsible for check & balance
- Support Local & net to perform their job for the best
- CCTV Configuration & Monitoring
- CCTV Backup with date & time

- Check audit cameras of vehicles in our times
- Data organized with folder date and time
- Responsible for daily checkups of CCTV in every department. If the CCTV is not working well then it's
- My duty to find the problem and resolve it on time for their best performance
- The daily report includes Backups, CCTV Records, Intercoms Records, etc.
- Ensure that printers, cartridges, and other equipment are fully stocked and ready for use
- Perform light maintenance on equipment and systems in order to prevent problems or errors
- Ensure software updates are installed and bugs are fixed as needed
- Troubleshoot software and hardware problems that are reported and resolve them
- Weekly report (All user's systems checkups)
- ERP is also workable & to perform print facility to all of the users
- Network cabling
- Printer troubleshooting & also scanner
- Compressing on a daily basis photos & uploading them to the server
- To check on daily CCTV footage with a list of details
- DVRs & NVRs Checkups
- Installation in all systems from the server

Graphic design expert

Fiverr [10/10/2019 - Current]

City: Remote work Country: Pakistan

I worked as a Graphic designer on Fiverr and offline clients. I have more than 4 years of skill experience in Graphics Designing.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Msc Computer Science

The University of Law [Current]

City: London

Country: United Kingdom

Website: https://www.law.ac.uk/

Master of Art

University of Peshawar [19/06/2023]

City: Peshawar
Country: Pakistan

Website: http://www.uop.edu.pk/

Bachelor of Art

University of Peshawar [07/08/2018 – 31/12/2020]

Address: peshawar pakistan, 25000 Peshawar (Pakistan)

Website: http://www.uop.edu.pk/

Diploma of Information Technology (DIT)

khyber pakhtunkhwa technical board [06/04/2016 - 20/12/2017]

Address: peshawar pakistan, 25000 peshawar (Pakistan)

Website: https://kpbte.edu.pk/

FSC

Board of intermediate & secondry education peshawar [06/05/2014 - 30/07/2016]

Address: peshawar pakistan, 25000 Peshawar (Pakistan)

Website: https://www.bisep.edu.pk/

SSC

Board of intermediate & secondry education peshawar [04/02/2012 - 18/06/2014]

Address: peshawar pakistan, 25000 Peshawar (Pakistan)

Website: https://www.bisep.edu.pk/

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Outlook, Facebook, Google / Installation and Maintenance of CCTV Cameras / LAN network configuration / Graphics Design Adobe Photoshop Sketchup / freelancing / Computer Operating / Computer Troubleshooting and Repair / Operating system: Windows

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Computer, Problem Solving, Inventing new things, Browsing, Vloging, Social Media

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Pushto

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user